Contact

shauhami020@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/shaunhamilton-411636114 (LinkedIn) shaunshamilton.github.io/portfolio/ (Portfolio)

Top Skills

DevOps
Data Annotation
Programming

Certifications

Quality Assurance
Front End Libraries
APIs and Microservices
Deep Learning Onramp Certificate

Shaun Hamilton

Software Developer at freeCodeCamp

Howick, KwaZulu-Natal, South Africa

Summary

Mechanical Engineer working as a Software Developer. Keen interest in computer science. Full-Stack Web Developer experience as well as SolidWorks, MATLAB, Python, and Rust. Previous work consists of Student Ambassador, Software Developer, Web Assistant, and Small-Plant Mechanic.

Experience

freeCodeCamp

5 years 9 months

Software Developer

May 2021 - Present (4 years 3 months)

Overseeing curriculum development and instructional design

Overseeing the freeCodeCamp GitHub organisation repositories, participating on issues, and quality assuring pull requests

Developing new features and services

Moderator

November 2019 - Present (5 years 9 months)

Glasgow, United Kingdom

Moderate GitHub issues and pull-requests, and forums for freeCodeCamp.org. I assist with debugging, and submitting pull-requests for issues, as well as dealing with the triage. Make sure all posts added to the forum are within the organisation's guidelines, as well as assist in answering questions and giving advice to members of the community on the topic of programming. GitHub issues and pull-requests are vetted against standards before being approved.

Pareto.Al

Al Trainer

March 2024 - May 2024 (3 months)

Annotated an Al Assistant's code suggestions for TypeScript and Rust projects.

MathWorks Student Ambassador September 2019 - January 2021 (1 year 5 months) Glasgow, United Kingdom

Worked as the first Student Ambassador for MathWorks at the University of Glasgow to promote MathWorks' software, and to educate students and staff in using the software. Created and posted posters around campuses to advertise events. Sourced venues, equipment, and food for events. Created and presented presentations demonstrating MATLAB and Simulink. Created and administered a Facebook group for students to follow and learn more about MathWorks, as well as transitioned to an internal MathWorks Community Group for testing.

Handprints e-NABLE Scotland Handprints Intern June 2019 - September 2019 (4 months) Glasgow, United Kingdom

Worked as one of nine members on the Handprints Myoelectric Summer Project setup by e-Nable Scotland. Designed and 3D printed prosthesis for children. Actively assisted with the research and innovation for a prosthetic hand controlled by myoelectics. Designed and developed the wikidot site used for deploying the design to the community.

Inyatsi Construction Group Holdings (Pty) Ltd Mechanic August 2017 - September 2017 (2 months)

Worked in the Small-Plant yard, maintaining and servicing the machinery.

Hardware Solutions Swaziland
IT Assistant
May 2017 - June 2017 (2 months)
Worked in one of NPCs franchises to help set up the website.

Education

University of Glasgow

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Mechanical Engineering · (2018 - 2021)

Glasgow International College

Foundation Certificate in Engineering, Engineering · (2018 - 2018)

Waterford Kamhlaba United World College IBDP, Engineering · (2015 - 2016)